Guide to the Laura (Riding) Jackson and Schuyler B. Jackson collection, 1924-1991
Jackson, Laura (Riding) and Schuyler B., 1924-1991
- Series IV. Literary Manuscripts
  - Unpublished Works
    - Letters to Editors
      - The Times Literary Supplement, November 11, 1973 ts. 3pp. + 3a; ts., 3pp. + 3a carbon; note ms. 1p.; draft letter ms. 1p.; two clippings (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - Library Journal, November 27, 1973 ts. 2pp.; ts. 22pp. carbon; clipping (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - Library Journal, July 5, 1975 ts. 2pp. carbon (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The New Statesman, August 6, 1975 ts. 2pp carbon; includes letter from Mark Jacobs to The New Statesman, August 6, 1975 ts. 1p. (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The New York Times Book Review, September 20, 1975 ts. 3pp. photocopy (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - London Magazine, April 12, 1976 ts. 3pp. accompanying letter ts. 1p. Apr. 16, 1976 revised letter ts. 1p. Apr. 25, 1976 letter to Alan Ross ts. 1p. Apr. 25, 1976 letter Ross to L(R)J ts. 1p. Apr. 15, 1976 letter to Ross ts. 1p. May 26, 1976 letter to Ross ts. 3pp. carbon Aug. 22, 1976 (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - London Magazine, August/September 1976, pp. 90-92, photocopy; three copies of the revisions ts. 3pp.; letter from James Atlas to London Magazine, 2 photocopy, pp. 96-97, photocopy (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - London Magazine, April 1977 ts. 2pp. 2ts. 2pp. photocopy (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The Times Literary Supplement, November 11, 1976, ts. 2pp. carbon (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The Times Literary Supplement, December 17, 1976, ts. 1p. carbon + clipping of J.S. Atherton' review of Published in Paris, by Hugh Ford (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The Scotsman, September 28, 1980, ts. 2pp.; ts. 2pp.; clipping about Laura Riding's literary partnership with Robert Graves in The Scotsman, [September 6, 1980], pp. 357-8, photocopy (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - English, June 10, 1981 ts. 7pp. carbon (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The New York Review of Books, June 29, 1987 ts. 2pp.; 2ts. 1p. carbon (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Editorial Activities
      - "Comments on a study of my work--a draft, unpublished" n.d., ts. 109pp.; "Commentary by Laura (Riding) Jackson" ms. 1p. [commentary on the draft of a dissertation by Joyce Wexler, yet to be submitted at the time], n.d. (Box 96, Folder 12)
      - "Drafts of the review of the English edition of Selected Poems: In Five Sets that eventually appeared in the English magazine The Cambridge Quarterly, by Michael Kirkham" ts. 6pp.; ts. 7pp.; note 2ms.1p., n.d. (Box 96, Folder 13)
- Series V. Broadcasts, Recordings, and Readings
  - "Four Unposted Letters to Catherine: Preface" ["Written in 1963 for the BBC's reading, on July 15 and 16, 1963 of the Four Unposted Letters to Catherine, especially revised for the reading..."] ts. 2pp.; ts. 2pp. carbon; ts. 2pp. photocopy" "Four Unposted Letters for Catherine. Modifications for Reading" ts. 6pp. "Unposted Letters to Catherine, by Laura Riding" (July 15th and 16th, 1963) ts. 25pp. (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - [Notes and transcripts of reading recorded at Lamont Library, Harvard College, January 1972] ms. 16pp.; 2ts. 5pp.; ts [4pp.]; ts. 8pp.; ts. 8pp carbon; ts. 10pp.; ts. 6pp.; ts. 6pp. photocopy (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - "Library of Congress Recording. Corrections" ms. 1p; ts. 1p; ms. 2pp. (Box 97, Folder 3)
- Series VI. Professional activities
  - [Memorandum of agreement between Georg Schwarz and the Seizin Press, July 14, 1936][Applications for grants] "Application for Fellowship for American Council of Learned Societies," February 1973, and 1975-76; forms, biographical data; list of publications; correspondence. (Box 97, Folder 4)
- Series VII. Other Activities
  - The Wabasso Development Project
    - "The Wabasso Story" [variously titled] ts. 2pp.; ts. 2pp. carbon. ts 5pp.; ts. 4pp.; ts. 4pp. carbon; ts. 2pp.; ts. 2pp.; ms 12pp.; ms. 12pp. carbon; ms./ts. working draft which includes numerous version of several pages (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, Jun. 1973-Oct. 1978 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Documents pertaining to the Wabasso Development Project and incoming correspondence, See also: correspondence from the American Council of Learned Societies in Series III. Correspondence. Incoming. (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Clippings pertaining to Wabasso Development Project (Box 98)
- Series VIII. Writings about Laura (Riding ) Jackson and Schuyler Benjamin Jackson
  - Biographical works
    - "Schuyler Brinckerhoff Jackson" in Princeton Alumni Weekly, vol. LXIX, no. 30, July 1, 1969, pp. 17-18 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Laura Riding Jackson, Cornell Alumni News, December 1973, p. 33 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Laura Riding Jackson, Cornell Alumni News, November 1975, p. 32 [entire issue] (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Critical Reception of L(R)J's Works
    - Book Reviews
      - Current Literature (1972), pp. 492-3, photocopy (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "Forgeries of Ourselves" by Judith Thurman [review of Selected Poems in Five Sets, The Nation, November 30, 1974, pp. 570-1] (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "Of The Telling" by Robert Ward, Reynard, Summer 1975, no. 29, pp. 22-23 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "Period Pieces" by Edwin Morgan, Times Higher Education Supplement, March 5, 1976, photocopy (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "Robert Graves' Collected Poems" by Alan Clark, TLS, Jan. 23, 1976, p. 85, clipping (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "Minds so wasted, people so tiresome" by William French [review of Thomas S. Matthews' Jacks or Better, in The Globe and Mail, Dec. 15, 1977, p. 16] clipping (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "The voice that stopped" by Robert Nye, The London Times, Sept. 9, 1980, clipping (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "The Poems of Laura Riding" St. Mark's Poetry Project Newsletter (March 1981), ts. 3 pp. (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - "Excerpt from review by Edwin Muir of 'Progress of Stories' Listener, March 25, 1936" ts. 1p. (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Miss Riding's Lucky Bag" by Rebecca West [review of Progress of Stories, Sunday Times, Jan 26, 1936] clipping (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Nine and Two" by SBJ, Time December 1938, pp. 41-44; note ms. 1p. (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Riding, Laura," Book Review Digest, 1939, p. 818 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Current Literature" English Studies (Holland) Vol. 54, no. 5 (1967), pp. 479-494 [see in particular pp. 492-3]"Nothing but the truth" by Ian Hamilton, in: The Observer, Aug. 9, 1970, n.p., clipping (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Laura Riding's Poems" by Michael Kirkham The Cambridge Quarterly, Vol. V, No. 3, 1971, pp. 302-8 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - [Review of The Telling by Alan Clark published under 'Book Notes' Research Communications. Braziers Park School of Integrative Social Research, 25/26 October 1972, ts. pp. 1-2; publisher's galley proof, 1p.] (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "The Telling" review by Frances H. Cheney, Tennessean[?] Dec. 16, 1973, n.p., clipping (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "The Telling" [Review by H. P. Collins, The Aryan Path, Vol. XLIV, No. 7, 1973, p. 325] clipping; with a clipping of a review of Collins' book on modern poetry (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Autobiography of the Present" review by James Atlas, Poetry, Vol. CXXV, no. 5 (February 1975), pp. 295-302, clipping; photocopy with L(R)J's comments (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "The Return of Laura Riding" review by Paul Auster The New York Review of Books, Aug. 7, 1975, pp. 36-8, clipping (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Mark Jacobs on Laura Riding" PN Review 15 (Vol. 7, no. 1) [1980], pp.62-5 [entire issue] (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Hard and Cool: The Poems of Laura Riding" by John Heath-Stubbs [ The Tablet, October 11, 1980, n.p.] (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - "Enduring Witness" by Martin Dodsworth, The Guardian, Nov. 6, 1980, clipping (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Comments and essays in literary magazines and anthologies
      - "Comments on Collected Poems (1938)" [includes comments transcribed by L(R)J] ts. 1p. (Box 99, Folder 4)
      - "On A Trojan Ending--Some Comments" ts. pp. 1-4] (Box 99, Folder 4)
      - "Writing by AJC [Alan Clark] for PN Review, to mark the 90th birthday of Laura (Riding) Jackson) Apologia (14 December 1990)" [unpublished] ts. 11pp.; ts. pp. 1B-13B (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - [entries in literary histories or anthologies; includes "Laura Riding's Pursuit of Truth, by Joyce Wexler"] ts. 8pp. (Box 99, Folder 6)
      - [ads and publishers' announcements of L(R)J's works] (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Entries in reference works
      - [entries in dictionaries and encyclopedias]1932, 1971 (Box 99, Folder 8)
      - [entries in catalogs and bibliographies] (Box 99, Folder 9)
- Series IX. Writings by others
  - "Morning Papers" by George Buchanan, bound typescript, 159pp. with comments by L(R)J, March 13, 1968, ms. 4pp.; May 27, 1969, ms. 1p. (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - [Poems by Robert Nye: "The Looking Glass" clipping, 1p.; "The Dark Heart" ts. 1p., originally inserted in the volume Juvenilia. 1 (London: Scorpion Press, 1961) donated to L(R)J by the author] (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - "In presenting his re-written and abridged versions ..." from a draft of Mark Jacobs and Alan Clark, "The Question of Bias: Some Treatments of Laura (Riding) Jackson," Hiroshima Studies in English Language and Literature, 21, 1976, 29pp.; ts. 1p. (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - "The Absolute of Poetry" ts. 12pp. carbon [by Allen Tate?], n.d. (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - "Another Future of Poetry" by Robert Graves, pp. 30-33, photocopy, 1926 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - [Dust jacket of Nancy Cunard: Brave Poet, Indomitable Rebel, 1896-1965, edited by Hugh Ford (1968) (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - [clippings of various works on language and literature, which are not by and do not mention L(R)J; includes a few notes by L(R)J], 1971-1981 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - [Material on authors with personal or literary connections with L(R)J; includes a few notes by L(R)J] (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - "Reflections on the Agrarians" by William E. Leverette, in Vanderbilt Alumnus (Winter 1981), pp. 7-24, photocopy (Box 100, Folder 8)
- Series X. Photographs
  - 15 black and white photographs of L(R)J, Schuyler Jackson, family members, and of two paintings of L(R)J; some identification provided by L(R)J (Box 101, Folder 1-5)
- Series XI. Memorabilia
  - Postcards of Montauban-de-Bretagne (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Engraving of painting: "Mrs. Schuyler firing her corn fields on the approach of the British" (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Deed poll changing surname from Gottschalk to Riding, December 9, 1927 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Certificate granting exemption from the Aliens Restriction Act of 1919, allowing use of the name Laura Riding, London, April 14, 1928 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Certificate of honorary membership to the Eugene Field Society granted to Laura Riding, St. Louis, September 7, 1939 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Schuyler Benjamin Jackson's U.S. Army Air Forces service certificates, 1943-1944 (Box 101, Folder 11)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books that were given as gifts to Laura (Riding) Jackson and were originally part of this collection have been separated and added to the rare book collection in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections at Cornell University, where other Laura (Riding) Jackson titles are located. Most carry autograph dedications.
Rose Forbes (London: Faber & Faber, n.d.) by George Buchanan
Green Seacoast (London: Gaberbocchus Press, 1959) by George Buchanan
Conversation with Strangers (London: Gaberbocchus Press, 1961) by George Buchanan
Bodily Responses (London: Gaberbocchus Press, 1958) by George Buchanan
A Grief Observed (New York: The Seabury Press, 1961) by C.S. Lewis
Juvenilia 1 (London: Scorpion Press, 1961) by Robert Nye
Juvenilia 2 (London: Scorpion Press, 1963) by Robert Nye
March Has Horses' Ears (London: Faber & Faber, 1966) by Robert Nye